Hello and welcome to the Katie Halper
Show. I'm Katie Helper. So excited to be
here and to be joined by
none other than
Leslie Lee the third.
Helper. So excited to be here.
Hey, none other than none other than
tech a little echo
issue. One second guys.
Hey,
too many windows open. God, sometimes
when you have the windows open. Hi,
Kelly. Hey, are you
Yeah, you're live. We are live. You're
live with You're like byebye. Okay. So,
it's nice to It's nice when I have
YouTube open another window because I
see how unclear
uh I am, which I don't know why that is.
We got to figure that out.
I feel like this is a like a almost
slapstick scene where it it gets
increasingly louder like the special
effects like jangling keys.
dog chewing something.
Uh, what would come next? Like a
cracking of an egg.
All right. Well, glad to see you guys.
Hi, David Melford. Hi, um, everyone
else. Uh, Echo No more. Thumbs up, like.
Yes, please like. Please like and share
this stream. Please subscribe if you
don't already subscribe.
And uh, we have a great show for you
guys tonight. we have with us joining
us. Uh, oh wow, this is great. I gotta I
gotta highlight this comment. Frank
Capria says, "When I had COVID, watching
the whole Katy Halper show was the only
good thing about having CO." Wow, thank
you. That is so nice.
Um, so we have a great show for you guys
today and uh we are going to be talking
to John Kuryaku who is a former CIA
analyst. And you know the good news,
guys, is that when something bad
happens, you want people to be held
accountable, right? Held responsible.
And what's great is that we all know and
hate and love, hopefully hate, we all
know and hate the CIA torture program,
right? And
the good thing is that someone went to
jail over that. The bad thing is that
the person who went to jail over that is
the person who blew the whistle on that,
which is a pretty um Orwellian thing to
to think about. And that's who our guest
is tonight. And he's someone who was a
CIA analyst. He's a whistleblower. He's
the author of several books. And he is
uh probably like uh one of the best
sources on discussing 9/11, uh pulling
out of Afghanistan, things like that. Uh
but sadly he's not ever uh sought out by
the mainstream media. So you wouldn't
see him on MSNBC on CNN. In fact, we're
going to he's going to share some
stories about how he's treated by those
networks, which uh interestingly enough
is not uh in a particularly appropriate
professional way. But before we get to
that, oh, and hi. Thanks from London and
Venezuela.
Greetings from London.
There's a Do you hear some background
noise, Leslie?
Um,
is your Is that your right mic? Because
I hear some Or is that something else?
I hear like an Argentine. It was almost
like a tango.
Um,
hold on one second. Let me see.
Sure. All right. Someone asked me why I
dragged them through my tech problems. I
don't know what what why. because I I
like doing that. It's not like we don't
do a tech run before things just happen.
Tell Abby Martin I'm live. Why?
Why am I Why do I Okay, it's the CIA
tapping the stream. It could be that.
Yeah.
Um the Katie Halber show is a proven
cure. It's true. Hi from Costa Rica.
Wow, we got we got a really
international audience. And by the way,
yeah, why not? Why should I not walk you
through my tech problems or drag as the
verb is? Thank you, Robert. You know,
some people some people are visionaries.
And when I say some people, that
includes Robert Nichols, perhaps most of
all. Um, oh, out in left field. I
subscribed to Katie four years ago. Uh,
on YouTube. I was so happy when she
finally got on YouTube. Hi, Katie.
A chat
uh where is this? A chat from
Philadelphia. Hi Katie, Leslie and chat
from Philadelphia. Hello Philadelphia.
Good evening Philadelphia.
Uh Carne Verde points out Kiraaku's
story is not complimentary toward uh
many defense department advertisers on
most media outlets. It's true. So it's a
good sign that he's treated like crap by
them. Um someone is saying hi from
Guantanamo Bay. I'm glad the conditions
have improved so much that you can watch
the Katie Helper show and have good
enough internet to sign in and say hi.
Hey Katie Helper, this show distresses
me. I think you mean like Yes, that's
how you spell it, right? Like destresses
me, not distresses me.
Um, okay. And then Sparky wants me to
ask about five eyes controlling the MSM
narrative. I feel like that's a
reference I don't get, but you may get.
Do you know what that means, Leslie?
Five eyes. If not,
no. Not off the top of my head.
Okay. Off the top of your head. Okay.
You're better on on
covert conspiracy things than I am.
Maybe it's not even a conspiracy theory.
Anyway, we'll see. Okay. Cool. New logo,
Leslie. Oh, yeah. I need I need my logo
up there. Um maybe Nick can throw that
up.
The little Katy Halbisher thing that
goes in the corner. Oh, hello from
Canada. When does the party start? The
party already started.
Um,
oh, five eyes are the governments of US,
UK, Canada, Australia, and New Zealand.
Ah, interesting. All English speaking.
All right.
Five eyes. Shouldn't that be one, two,
three, four, five? 10 eyes.
Just saying. All right. Well, we'll get
more into the five eyes uh shortly. Um,
oh, there's a really funny clip. We
Well, we'll watch that later about uh
Did you guys see Did you see that clip
going around? Uh, anyone see that clip
going around in the chat from the show I
think called Utopia uh with Australia
choosing to like declare war on China?
Anyway, I'll I'll find I'll find out.
But uh before we bring uh John in,
Leslie, how was your week and any
updates that you like to share either
from your personal life or political
life? Well, this weekend, um, as
everybody knows, was the, uh, was the
20th, uh, anniversary of September 11th,
and I got to watch former President
Trump celebrate, uh, this and give his
tribute to this by calling uh, a freak
show boxing fight. Um, President Donald
Trump, yes, that that Donald Trump,
former president, was actually
commentating. Uh he spent the day in New
York, but then he flew down to Florida
to do some commentary on this boxing
show headlined by the 58-year-old
Evander Holyfield being TKO'ed by Vor
Bellforth in a really really a match
that probably should not have legally be
allowed to take place because I
Holyfield even though he's in amazing
shape um not he's 60 years old, he's old
man. He's just an old man. And to see
Donald Trump there commentating on it
and it his commentary was so bizarre
because even though he goes to all these
boxing events, he doesn't know anything
about it. You know that the old trope
about like how oh in like a sitcom like
the wife will watch football and she'll
just start cheering for the team with
the most with the most attractive
uniforms. That's how Trump approaches
like boxing. Uh he keep even though he's
been going for 20 years, he still keeps
talking about like he kept talking about
during the event like, "Oh, that guy, he
looks so beautiful. He's in such great
shape. Like he must be win, right?" He
literally asked the MMA guys like how
come like sometimes the most attractive
fighter doesn't win. Like he he did not
understand that the hottest guy does
isn't always going to win uh the fight.
He didn't understand.
Well, that's because uh that's because
he is a winner. He won the presidency.
So he the lesson he learned is the hot
guy wins.
Yes. Yes. And that's why he was so sad
about losing to Biden because I think he
has an argument. I think he has an
argument. Hey, maybe he's a little bit
hotter than Biden.
Oh my gosh. I don't know. I I can't even
terrible. Would you rather? Yeah, I
know.
That's like uh that or or cutting off my
leg. I'm not sure which of those three
scenarios. Yeah, but it was a it was a
fun show but very strange like
culturally because Triller Fights is
like this it's like a like some kind
sort of like scam that all these
celebrities are invested in. I don't
know. I'm sure there's Saudi money
involved but like they're appealing to
the MAGA crowd with Trump, but they're
also like their whole promotion is like
very like youthleaning and like hiphop
oriented. So it's like also trying to
advertise to like young black kid and
Hispanic kids while also like having
like old like white people who like
Donald Trump want to buy and see. It was
very very very strange like mashup of
these cultures that uh you could watch
for $50 and I I couldn't think of a
better way to celebrate to you know
to It was America. It was America. a
woman interrupted the 10 bell salute for
September 11th victims and started
screaming and most people assumed she
was screaming screaming at Donald Trump
because the camera was on Trump and it
was he was trying to look his most
somberest uh with there and Donald
Junior was there too. Um and but the
woman was actually screaming because she
didn't want to wear a mask.
She was screaming about the m I don't
even know if she had to wear a mask.
Most people weren't wearing masks. I
think she was just screaming about the
mask restrictions existing. That's how
mass
the Holocaust.
Yeah. She was literally at
slavery and the Holocaust combined is
the mask mandate.
Yeah. So it was like she was so m she
was at this event with Donald Trump
during a 911 tribute. Very somber. Uh,
and she was still so mad about the fact
that in some places there's a mask
mandate that she felt the need to
interrupt it in front of the person who
I'm sure she voted for twice like it was
it looked like a good moment for him
like that some he get to he got to be
there and be very somber and then this
woman just starts screaming bloody
murder about something or another while
Trump's there. very embarrassing uh
night, at least at the start, because he
was really not into the fights. He was
like exhausted at like 6:00 p. p.m. Uh
or
Trump was Trump was he did not want to
be there until he was joined by like
some actual fighters, a fighter named
Jorge Masadol and then Junior Dostos.
They're both like MAGA like MMA
fighters. He talked about like, "Oh
yeah, these guys helped me win Miami by
30 points. first time Republicans ever
done that. And he got as so when he
replaced like the MMA commentators who
are just these like nerds with like the
hot MMA fighters, Trump started getting
really into it and excited about it.
What do you think it is? He just like
gets excited. What do you think it is?
He likes being around hot guys. I I
don't know what else to say. He likes
being around hot fit guys. He's very
much like uh Vince McMahon uh in a
sense. Vince McMahon also thought that
the hottest uh guy should always a
buffest guy should win every fight.
That's why he did pro wrestling to make
that a true, you know, story. But Trump
wants it in MMA and boxing and he's
confused by why that doesn't happen.
So Trump knows wrestling but not boxing.
Is that correct?
Well, or does he not know wrestling
either?
Well, he's very good at wrestling, I
think. How do I say this about Trump? He
is a natural heel. a natural heel.
And can you remind people like me what
heel is?
So a heel is a bad guy in wrestling and
a face is a good guy. And so Trump is
just kind of a natural heel. Like he
knows how like and a heel's point is to
uh get the get people mad at them,
right? So the matter you get a heel,
you're just responding to the the more
you boo the heel, the better he's doing
at his job and the happier he is.
Oh, like trolls. They're like
Yeah. Well, yeah, kind of. But that's
the key thing to understanding like
that's what kayfabe is all about. Like
you think that when you go
remind people what kayfabe is.
Kayfabe just means fake. It's kind of
the you know the idea that you know
wrestling is taking place and it's the
matches are predetermined right? So when
you go down there and boo you know Rody
Piper and yell at him you're not hurting
his feelings. That's what he wants you
to do. That's his job. If you stop going
to do that, then Rody Piper loses his
job. And so, uh, that helps with
understand politics because, you know,
lots of things Trump did piss people
off, but it's like he wanted people to
be pissed off about that or that's all
it's all part of the show. I I would say
Trump versus Biden celebrity
presidential death match. That would be
good.
Uh let's I just want before we bring on
the guests, I just want to show this is
this is when I think of uh
uh Trump and wrestling, this is what I
think of. You guys remember this?
Hold on. Remember this tweet?
Oh yeah,
he does know pro wrestling. He did do I
He did do a very sloppy Lariat move.
He's is not a very good move.
What's that move?
That's called a lariat, but he doesn't
do it real well. You're supposed to do
more force so that when you hit the
person with your arm, they're going
down. Like, he kind of falls on top of
the guy.
Kind of kind of just falls on top of
him.
So, it's not it's not a very good Larry.
In fact, one of the earliest episodes of
Struggle Session, which you can find at
patreon.com/struggression,
we invited an actual real life
championship pro wrestler, Nicole
Matthews, to uh evaluate Trump's uh
wrestling ability. And frankly, she did
not she was not impressed.
Oh, okay. So, that wasn't good wrestling
that he did there.
Yeah. See, we tried to take Trump down
very early on. People should have
listened to us. We told we tried to tell
people that he was bad at pro wrestling
and nobody listened to us. We we tried
to stop him. he never would have been
elected.
And as goes uh pro wrestling goes uh
being president over the United States.
So that should have been a warning. You
tried. We all did our best to take him
down.
Um speaking of uh Patreon, I want to
thank everyone who supports this show on
Patreon. I also want to encourage people
to support the show on Patreon.
patreon.com/thekatyhelper
show. And if you do that, you get your
name read and you even get a little poem
written about you. So, um, I'm going to
thank some recent, uh, Patreon donors to
this show. And if I've skipped you or
missed you, just let me know in the
chats and I will read your names. And
also, uh, remember, you have this
entire, uh, show to become Patreon
supporters in a way that will get you
featured on the show. So, here is who
I'm thanking right now. Ready?
Susan Pari, you come from Rich
Parentage.
And I say that because you share the
last name with Christian Parent and
Michael Parent.
Great story.
Great. Yes. And uh great intellectuals,
great speakers also. Um who else do we
got? We also have a new Patreon
supporter,
Fender Gibson.
That is a fender bender of a donation
that we got from him. Just a fender
bender of a donation. So, thank you so
much for that. Uh, who writes the poems?
I write the poems. I know you can't tell
because they seem so uh
professional and and baroque.
Are you being ghostwritten by Amanda
Gorman? Perhaps, you know, Kanye West
even.
I I both of them actually in real time
at the same time. Um, but uh, so that's
that's that's the show so far. What do
what else do we want to talk about? I
think should we just get into that into
the interview because our guest is so
good. I really want to get as much time
from him as possible. What do you what
say ye?
Yes. Yes, we did.
All right. So, our guest tonight is John
Kiryaku, a former CIA analyst and former
case officer and former counterterrorism
consultant for MSNBC News and lifelong
whistleblower, exposing after he left
the CIA the US's illegal and immoral
torture policy practiced by the US
government during the Iraq war. Um, one
second, there's more. Do not you worry.
Um
he is a uh former senior investigator
for the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee and former counterterrorism
consultant for ABC News. He was
responsible for the capture in Pakistan
in 2002 of Abu Zubay I can't say this
right Abu Zubaya believed to be the
third ranking official in al-Qaeda. In
2007, Kuryaku blew the whistle on the
CIA's torture program, saying that the
CIA tortured prisoners, that torture was
official US government policy, and that
the policy had been approved by then
President George W. Bush. He became the
sixth whistleblower indicted by the
Obama administration under the Espionage
Act, a law designed to punish spies. He
served 23 months in prison as a result
of the revelation. Kuryaku won the Penn
Center USA's prestigious first amendment
award in 2015, the first blueprint
international whistleblowing prize for
bravery and integrity in the public
interest in 2016, and the Sam Adams
Award for Integrity and Intelligence,
also in 2016. Kuryaku is the author of
The Reluctant Spy: My Secret Life in the
CIA's War and Terror, Doing Time Like a
Spy, How the CIA Taught Me to Survive
and Thrive in Prison, The Convenient
Terrorist, and Abu Zubaya and the Weird
Wonderland of America's Secret Wars. So,
without any further ado, let us bring
onto the stream John Kuryaku. Hello.
Hey, thanks for having me, Katie.
Of course. Thank you so much for
joining.
Well, it's my pleasure and thanks to
everybody. I can't believe how many
people are already on and commenting.
So, this is going to be a lot of fun.
Thank you.
Yeah, people are really excited that
you're here and you should be on every
network. Um, but surprisingly uh are
not. Uh, and I just coincidentally
before I booked you uh no, sorry, after
I booked you, I saw that you were on uh
with Bob Sheer. It was a great interview
and one of the things that he was
pointing out was why I mean this is a
time when people like you should be
sought after. Um there not that many
people like you though, but you should
be sought after. You know, you're
someone with inside knowledge who's
actually willing to talk about these
things in ways that are
honest, but that's also exactly why
you're not asked to talk. You know, I
don't I don't want to sound cynical, but
all these networks have their have their
retired fourstar generals that they need
to put on uh the air. And um
and it's it's funny
after I after I blew the whistle, uh I
was frozen out of of the big news
networks. And then
a couple of times I had invitations from
CNN,
once from MSNBC, the Ari Melbour show.
And then when Trump got elected, um, I
was getting more requests from Fox than
I could handle. And it was because they
wanted me to jump up and down and yell
about the Obama administration
uh, waging a war on whistleblowers.
So, you know, that was that was one of
those points where the enemy of my enemy
was my friend. But as soon as Donald
Trump left, then that was the end of it
with Fox, too,
right? So now, well, lucky for us, lucky
for the Katie Halper show. We have a
near monopoly. We share you with Bob
Sheer. Yeah.
Well, well, there's one there's one
notable one. Uh Jared Leto, the Joker
himself, reached out to you and did an
interview. That's of all the people, one
of the most twisted minds in Hollywood,
but not MSNBC.
Crazy. I I was Jared Leto's uh high
school history teacher
um at at a small school in uh in
Washington. And I actually wrote him a
letter of recommendation to go to film
school.
Wow.
Yeah. And then he went to went on to win
an Academy Award for best supporting
actor. Terrific guy.
And he interviewed you?
He interviewed me on his show. He he has
a a web show that that did quite well.
And then when I won the pen award, I
asked him if he would introduce me, so
he was generous enough to do that.
Wow, that's great.
Yeah, it was fun.
Awesome.
Your so-called life.
Yes. Remember that?
Yeah,
that was that was a show that nobody
watched that the critics absolutely
loved and it put him on a path to
stardom.
Yeah, I remember that. Whatever happens
happens. That's something he said which
is sounds like Buddhist in the context
of what we're talking about. But um can
you tell people about how you wound up
in prison? Uh
because there like so many twists and
turns, but I I just think it's important
to remember that you are the person the
one person in prison over the CIA
torture program. So
yeah, the only one. Um, yeah. Uh, I I
led a raid in Pakistan on on the night
of March 22nd, 2002 that resulted in
At this point, you were the C you were
what?
I was the I was the chief of CIA
counterterrorism operations in Pakistan.
I had gotten to Pakistan in January of
2002. So, we had just finished bombing
Tora Bora. And my big claim to fame
there, I I guess I can say it now
because almost 20 years have passed was
we had these CIA officers all the way up
and down the border between Afghanistan
and Pakistan. And I said that that was
really really inefficient that we should
pull everybody off the border, bring
them into the cities, let the terrorists
come into the cities, and then we know
they're going to make a mistake because
they're always going to make a mistake.
Then we hit the safe house and we grab
everybody at once. And that actually
worked. And so we caught many dozens,
I'm not allowed to say the number of
alleged uh al-Qaeda terrorists that
night, including Abu Zuba, who we
believed at the time was the number
three in al-Qaeda. He was not the number
three. He was not even a member of
al-Qaeda. He was a bad guy. He had
founded al-Qaeda's two training centers
in or training camps in southern
Afghanistan. He had founded what they
called the house of martyrs in Pashawar,
Pakistan. It was the safe house that
al-Qaeda used there uh to bring people
into and out of Afghanistan. And he was
kind of a logistics guy for al-Qaeda. If
you needed a passport, you needed a
ticket, you wanted to go fight, or you
were tired of the fight and you wanted
to go home, Abu Zub, Abu Zuba was your
guy. That's who you went to.
So we caught him and uh my orders that
night were to sit with him in the
hospital. A Pakistani policeman had shot
him three times with an AK-47 in the
groin, the stomach and the uh thigh. And
so my orders were not to leave his
bedside. So I I tore up a sheet. I tied
him to the bed and I sat there and we
talked a lot. And I said to him at one
point, listen, I'm going to give you
some advice,
I am the nicest guy that you're going to
meet in this experience. I said, my
colleagues, they're not nice like I am.
So, if there's one thing that you have
to do, it's that you have to cooperate.
And he said, "You seem like a nice man,
but you're the enemy, and I'll never
cooperate."
Well, finally the CIA sent in a a an
unmarked private jet to pick him up. Uh,
three FBI agents and I carried him out
on a gurnie to the plane. We maneuvered
him onto the plane. We put him on the
luggage rack at the back, tied him down,
and he squeezed my hand. And I said,
"Remember, you have to cooperate." But
he was very upset. He he cried a lot. He
said he would never know the touch of a
woman. He would never know the joy of
fatherhood. And I said, "Listen, you're
not the victim here. There were 50,000
people in those towers. What did you
think we were going to do? Did you think
we wouldn't try to find you or to find
Bin Laden?" And he said, "I never wanted
to attack the United States on September
11th. All I ever wanted to do was to
kill Jews." He said he wanted to attack
Israel. Nice guy, right?
Few.
So, um,
I said, "Your life is over.
what's left of it can be easy or it can
be terrible.
The choice is yours. Now, I I said that,
but I really didn't know what the CIA
had in store for him. I didn't know that
while this was all taking place at
headquarters, they were coming up with
this torture program.
So, uh, I got back to CIA headquarters
in May of 2002, and I was asked if I
wanted to, uh, be the words were trained
in the use of enhanced interrogation
techniques. I had never heard the term
before. So, I asked what it meant. And
this senior officer, after excitedly
saying, "We're going to start getting
rough with these guys," he told me what
they meant. And I said, "Ooh, I don't
know, man." I said, "That that sounds
like a torture program." No, he said, '
It's not a torture program. It was
approved by the Justice Department and
the White House. I said, 'Yeah, I don't
think I'm interested. I I actually
consulted a senior officer and he's
like, "Buddy," he said, "Run screaming
from the room. This is a terrible
mistake." So, I went back down and I
said, "I am not interested in this. I
think it's immoral. It's unethical and
it's certainly illegal." I actually got
passed over for promotion because I
turned it down. So um
I went about my business. I got promoted
because of Abu Zubeta. I became the
executive assistant to the CIA's deputy
director for operations. And so I was
able to follow the whole uh torture
program as it was playing out. But what
we were reading at headquarters was
actually a lie. What was really
happening was that Ali Sufan, an FBI
agent with whom I had worked in
Pakistan, um, and other FBI
interrogators had actually gotten Abu
Zuba to start talking. And they did that
the way they've been doing that since
the Nuremberg trials in 1945
by establishing a rapport by being
respectful by offering him you know an
orange or a cigarette or you know a
piece of paper and a pencil so he could
write to his mother which he was really
really worried about. He was very
worried that his mother would, you know,
think the worst. And um
make sure she knows that I just wanted
to kill Jews.
Yeah. Yes. And and she was so proud of
him after we we captured him. She
immediately ran to the media and she
said that she wished that all of her
sons and she had like nine sons. She
wished that all of her sons could have
made jihad against the Americans like
Abu Zubeda did. Wow. Wow.
It's like you might want to tell your
mom to stop talking.
Yeah. Wow. So,
yeah. I mean, for the sake of his
siblings, that's just so much pressure.
Yeah. Well, I was so appalled by this
torture program. I I left the agency and
I kept waiting for somebody to go
public. It was just so egregious. I
thought surely somebody is going to go
public and say something and nobody did.
Well, I let time pass. And then finally
in um in December of 2007 um I said
something in an interview to Brian Ross
at ABC News. As you might imagine, the
very next day the CIA filed what's
called a crimes report against me with
the FBI saying that I had revealed
classified information. And this is
where it gets weird. Um the FBI
investigated me from December of '07 to
December of '08. and then they closed
the case and they sent my attorneys a
declination letter, meaning they were
declining to prosecute me. So, my my
then wife and I were so happy that we
actually went out to dinner and
celebrated that night that that this
nightmare was over. But three weeks
later, when Barack Obama was inaugurated
and John Brennan became the deputy
national security adviser for
counterterrorism,
my troubles began a new. John and I were
not friendly. I had worked directly for
him. And then when I went up to the
seventh floor as the executive
assistant, John was the executive
director of the CIA, the number three
ranking officer in the CIA. and he was
one of the fathers of the torture
program.
And so he asked the Justice Department
to secretly reopen the case against me.
I had no idea that for the next 3 years
my phones were tapped, my emails were
intercepted, and teams of FBI agents
would periodically surveil me. And then
in January of 2012, I was arrested and
charged with five felonies, including
three counts of espionage.
Now, mind you, espionage sometimes
carries with it the death penalty.
Um, but I had the greatest lawyers in
Washington. I hadn't committed
espionage. Those charges were eventually
dropped, but uh, in the end, I had to
take a deal to make the whole thing go
away. Um, they were threatening me with
45 years. They offered me two
and I actually turned down the two
because I said I haven't done anything
wrong. And my lawyers said, "Look,
this study had come out from uh
ProPublica in October of 2012. It said
that the federal government wins 98.2%
of its cases." So, I had a 1.8%
chance of winning. I said, "If I lose
realistically, what am I looking at
here?" And they said, "Realistically, 12
to 18 years. Take the deal." And so I
took the deal. You know, there's this
there's this joke that everybody in
prison is innocent. I met a lot of
people in prison who were actually
innocent. But when they have essentially
the rest of your life hanging over your
head and they're offering you a fraction
of that to plead guilty, people plead
guilty.
You got to make the thing go away. One
of the things, this will be my last
thought on this issue. One of the things
that one of the lawyers told me, and
this was the lawyer that I liked and
trusted the most. I had 11 lawyers, if
you can imagine. He said, "This can be a
blip in your life or it can be the
defining event of your life. Make it the
blip." And so I took the deal.
Wow. So can you tell us more um
before we we move forward to what's
happening today about um what you
learned from um can you pron Abu Zaba
Abu Zaba what what you learned from him
how you learned what you learned from
him and what insight that gave you into
what I guess was behind for some people
uh the
uh the vitriil against the United states
uh and Israel.
Yeah, good question.
So, Abu Zubeda taught us a lot. Uh there
were two things that were the most
critical that came from Abu Zuba. First
of all,
the guy had a mind for detail that
I've rarely come across in my career.
Abu Zuba gave us al-Qaeda's wiring
diagram which we just never knew. We
knew that Osama bin Laden was the number
one that uh I had had been the number
two. Now he's the number one. And that
Muhammad Ata uh was the head of what
they called military affairs and and we
killed him. Uh I'm sorry, Muhammad Atef,
sorry. We killed him in October of 2001.
We just didn't know anything else about
al-Qaeda. We didn't know how it was
structured. We didn't know where it was.
And so Abu Zuba
said, and I'm going to use I'm going to
use this as an example.
He didn't say these specific words. What
he said was still or is still
classified, but to give you an idea,
we would ask him if if I wanted to carry
out an attack in let's say Dusseldorf,
how would I do that?
And he said, 'Well, in Dusseldorf,
there's this guy, Muhammad, and here's
his phone number. And Muhammad knows
this other guy, Abdullah, and Abdullah's
really good with bombs. And Abdullah has
this email, and Abdullah's cousin is a
guy named Rashid. And Rashid has access
to weapons. And this is the address
where Rashid keeps the weapons. So we
call the Germans, and we'd say, "Hey,
you have a problem in Dusseldorf." And
here's the information we have. And then
the Germans raid these addresses and
they grab Muhammad Abdullah and Rashid
and you know lives were saved.
So um that was the one thing that he was
really great at. The other thing that he
was really great at and it was dramatic
was we had never heard of Khaled Shikh
Muhammad. We just never heard the name
before. We knew that there was this guy
going by the nondigger Mkhtar. And we
knew that Mkhtar had been the mastermind
of what was supposed to be called the
Trebinka operation. I'm sorry, the
Bojinka operation. Forgive me. The
Bojink operation in 1996 was a plot to
hijack something like a half a dozen
747s in Manila and then fly them into
buildings up and down the west coast of
the United States.
Uh, word of this plot leaked and we were
able to break it up along with the
Filipinos, but all we knew is that it
was a guy named Mktar.
So when he mentioned Khalik Muhammad, we
we didn't know who that was and he
laughed and he said, "You don't know
Mktar?"
And that was the first time that we were
able to understand that Mktar was Khal
Shik Muhammad, which then gave us a
target, right? We have these targeting
analysts at the CIA
who um whose job it is to pour through
thousands, hundreds of thousands of
pages of data to try to locate somebody.
You know, most CI analysts, their job is
to think the big thoughts and write a
paragraph and write a second paragraph
of analysis and then send it to the
White House and hope that, you know, the
the deputy assistant to the president
for whatever reads it. And then you
influence policy. This is a completely
different job. This is there's a guy
named Ahmed Schmmed. I don't know where
he is. We need to kill him. You have to
find him. And then that's it. You know,
they they send you go to NSA. You go to
FBI. You you just use what's called all
source intelligence to try to geollocate
somebody so we can either grab them or
um or kill them. And so they put the
targeting analysts on Khalich Shake
Muhammad and two months later he was in
our custody. So that was the value of of
Abu Zuba. And I'll add one other thing
about Abu Zuba. And I feel very strongly
about this.
Abu Zubed has never been charged with a
crime. Never. Not in the United States
in any federal district. Not in the
military tribunal at Guantanamo.
Whether we like this guy's politics or
not is irrelevant. What is relevant is
that he has constitutional protections.
And so either we're a nation governed by
the rule of law and by this living
breathing constitution that we're all so
proud of, or we're not. And if you're
not going to charge him with a crime,
you have to let him go. Now, he's been
in our custody for almost 20 years. It's
going to be 20 years on March the 22nd
and he's never been charged with a
crime. And that's after going through
unspeakable torture, including where he
was he was taken into surgery without
his consent and had his eye removed.
So, we've we've really done a number on
this guy. Oh, yeah.
For any reason,
he had heard his eye um fighting the
Soviets. And so he had one brown eye and
one eye that was really really pale blue
because he had taken some shrap.
Yeah. He couldn't see from that eye, but
you know it never bothered him.
Yeah. You're allowed to Oh my god.
And so we drugged him one day and when
he woke up he had no eye.
What was the Was that just a power move?
Yeah. It was just Yeah. I mean
like a sadistic move like a That's it.
So disgusting. Oh my god.
That's why he we gave him
I mean I know I sound so naive. We're
talking about the CIA, the CIA and also
torture, but still that deep. Oh my
gosh.
That's why he refuses to wear a glass
eye. When you see pictures of him now,
it's always with an eye patch.
Yeah. He refuses. They gave him a glass
eye and he said absolutely not
cuz he like wants to to be in people's
faces. What happened?
What what we did to him. Mhm. And so the
other thing and and Robert Shear uh
pointed this out like the his and his
mind I mean how destroyed are these
people's minds? You were talking about
this in this interview like if it just
for for um
you know Machavelian reasons wouldn't we
want to not torture these people so that
they would be useful resources um for
information?
Oh my god. One of the things that that
we learned very quickly
is torture just simply doesn't work.
Right.
The moral, ethical stuff.
Yeah. Forget the whole moral, ethical,
legal question. Um, it just simply
doesn't work. A a a a person who's being
tortured will tell you anything that
that person thinks you want to hear,
whether it's true or not, just to get
you to stop torturing them. So, they
will give you this data dump of
information that you're going to have to
then assign an army of analysts to go
through to figure out what's true and
what's not true. While there might be
something true in there, there's
definitely stuff that's not true in
there. And you've just wasted all these
resources and 6 months. Now, there's
this what what they call the ticking
time bomb theory, right? There's a bomb
that's getting ready to go off in some
American city. We don't know where. We
need the information. like on Fox's 24
and we got to torture the guy to get the
information. That's not real life. That
doesn't happen ever in real life. Let's
say you torture the guy. He says the
bomb is in Chicago, Los Angeles,
Seattle, Houston, San Antonio, and
Philadelphia. Okay, now what do you do?
He just said there are bombs all over
the country. Now you got to figure out
what was true and what wasn't true. And
by the time you figure it out, the bomb
went off and killed everybody.
And that's besides the moral, legal, and
ethical issues.
And what kind of uh treatment did you
did you witness any of this or did you
just know about this?
No. When I turned down the uh the
torture training, um I I was just cut
off, right? I got passed over for
promotion. I they gave me the this
nickname the human rights guy which was
not a compliment,
right?
And so um
what nobody expected was that that six
weeks later I was going to get promoted
and go up to the seventh floor as the
executive assistant. And in that
position I had access to literally
everything that the CIA was doing around
the world. And that was just at the time
that they started torturing him. So I
got to see it and I I mentioned a few
minutes ago and I didn't explain myself
that what we knew or thought we knew at
the CIA was a lie. The truth is that Ali
Sufan, the FBI agent had established
this rapport with Abu Zuba and Abu Zuba
opened up and he was giving us that
Dusseldorf like information.
The CIA was furious that the FBI had
primacy over this case. Now, the FBI had
primacy because 9/11 was still an open
criminal investigation. But
historically, whenever something is
going on overseas, the CIA is in charge.
Whenever something is going on
domestically, the FBI is in charge. So,
here we were overseas at this secret
location, and the FBI is in charge. And
that enraged the CIA leadership.
I can't I can't explain
enough how deeply the CIA and the FBI
hated each other. We hated each other so
much that we didn't speak to one
another. And our computer systems
weren't even compatible. And and this is
the this is the operative point.
Ali Sufan was getting all this
intelligence from Abu Zuba. He was
writing it all up and sending it to the
FBI, right? The CIA had no idea that
this stuff was being reported because
the FBI wasn't sharing it. And so
George Tennant, who was the CIA director
at the time, went to President Bush and
asked President Bush to withdraw the um
the FBI from the secret site and let the
CIA take over. Now, why Bush agreed to
do that, he's never explained,
but the FBI was pulled out, the CIA took
over, and within two hours, they began
torturing Abu Zuba.
Well, what did he do? He completely went
silent. He just clammed up and stopped
telling his interrogators anything at
all. So what these two CIA contractors
did uh Mitchell and Jessen
uh is they found Ali Sufan's FBI
reports. They retyped them in the CIA
database and said, "Oh my god, we
waterboarded him one time and look what
he gave us. All this intelligence.
Somebody called the Germans. We got to
save Dusseldorf,
right? Mktar is Khaled Shake Muhammad.
Oh my god. And I said to a friend of
mine when the report came in, you know,
maybe I'm wrong. I've been on my high
horse about this being, you know, a
terrible policy and and it doesn't work.
Maybe it does work. That doesn't make it
moral or ethical, but I mean, they're
telling us he look at what he gave us.
He gave us the kitchen sink. Well, that
was all a lie. He had already given it
to Ali to Ali Sufan.
We didn't know that that was a lie until
the CIA inspector general's report was
declassified in 2009.
If you can imagine and we gave Mitchell
and Jessen $18
million of the taxpayers money to come
up with this torture program.
That's a crime.
So, just to to clarify, the CIA got the
program taken away from the FBI.
They used the information that the FBI
had already gotten from them.
Yes.
And then pretended that it was the
result of their interrogation to justify
because they knew nobody would would
check.
The hatred was so deep between the CIA
and the FBI and the computer systems
weren't compatible. They knew that
nobody would check and nobody did.
How many like disasters happened because
of that lack of It sounds like a dating
show or something. That lack of
compatibility between the CIA and the
FBI, but seriously, like
Well, well, the big one the big one was
9/11,
right? The the CIA knew that there were
these guys who meant to attack us inside
the United States. They even had several
of their names, their actual names,
including Osama bin Laden, right?
Including Osama bin Laden. But I'm
speaking specifically of the hijackers
themselves.
Oh, wow. Okay.
We had we had some of their names. We
knew that they were planning this
massive major attack and the FBI never
told us that they were in the United
States. And um
the FBI didn't say anything because the
FBI believed that they were recruitable.
And so they didn't want the CIA stepping
on their promotions. You know, if you
recruit somebody, you're going to get
promoted. You're going to get a medal.
You'll get an award.
The last thing you want is the CIA
coming to grab your people.
And so, you know, both sides fell asleep
at the switch.
It's so disgusting.
It's It's a little different now. Now,
there's an FBI agent who's the deputy
director of the CIA's counterterrorist
center, and there's a CIA officer who's
the deputy director of the FBI's
counterterrorist center. And people do
rotations back and forth. You know,
maybe you'll spend a year at the CIA and
I'll spend a year at the FBI and, you
know, we all go out for beers together
on Friday nights. That's supposed to fix
everything.
Also disgusting in a different way.
Yeah. Uh, and then of course you have
that with the media.
Oh my god, the situation with the media
is is worse than most Americans have any
idea. You know, there used to be this
thing called Operation Mockingbird. And
Mockingbird was where the CIA actively
recruited reporters, especially American
reporters, to plant stories. Now, we
have laws against propagandizing the
American people. You're not supposed to
do that. And the CIA stopped doing it
formally in 1975.
Well, now they do it publicly. So they
created this office of public affairs.
It has several different branches in it.
One branch deals solely with Hollywood
Studios. So that any mention of the CIA
is a positive one. That's how movies
like Zero Dark 30 get made or the
recruit. Uh there are never Hollywood
movies where the CIA guys are the bad
guys. Never. Um and the other one deals
with uh with national security
journalists.
Now there are national security
journalists out there
who are probably good journalists, but
they don't have a budget like they used
to have back in the day. And so they'll
just take whatever the CIA gives them,
they'll gist it and change some of the
wording and that's their article. So
what you end up having is a situation
where the CIA will tell journalists here
in Washington what to write
and they write it. Now, there's there's
one guy who's especially bad. Ken
Delaneian from MSNBC, formerly of the
Los Angeles Times.
Jason Leupold, who's a journalist with
BuzzFeed and a friend of mine, is the
king of the Freedom of Information Act.
He's done more Freedom of Information
Act requests than any other person in
America to the point where um a defense
department official called him a foyer
terrorist because he's gotten so much
information. He was the one that broke
the information about the uh Hillary
email server,
right? So, he sent a Freedom of
Information Act request to the CIA
asking for copies of all emails between
the CIA's Office of Public Affairs and
National Security Journalists. And what
that included was emails between
Kendallian
and the Office of Public Affairs where
Kendallian was writing pro-CIA articles
for NBC and MSNBC and he was sending
them back to the CIA for approval.
before he was sending them to his own
editor.
Well, that takes that one step. It's
efficient.
But what the CIA does, see, Kendallian
is one of the guys that they like. Um,
what they don't like is somebody like
Jason Leopold. And so they'll tell Jason
Leupold, "We want you to write this
article this way, and if you don't, we
will never speak to you again, and you
will never have access to any CIA
officer ever again." Well, Jason Leupold
said that's fine. He'll develop his own
sources. Thank you very much. But the
likes of Kendallian just do as they're
told.
Right. Yeah. Disgusting. Um,
couldn't looks like such a salt of the
earth guy. Never would have guessed it.
You know, he's he's a nice enough guy.
I've met him a couple of times. He's
always friendly.
Yeah.
But I wouldn't trust him as much as I
could pick him up and throw him.
Right. Um, and so how do you reveal? Can
you just share the context in which you
re you blow the whistle?
There's a right way to do it officially.
Oh, wait. Really quickly before then.
Yeah. How public are you about your beef
with Brennan? I don't know the answer to
what the beef is, but
I'm I'm public with my beef.
I mean, we know that that that beef is
there, but do we What about the cause?
You know, I I don't know why John
Brennan never liked me. I I when I
worked for him, he was perfectly nice
enough. I was not one of the, you know,
one of the in guys. We didn't hang out
at his house to watch football like
everybody else in my branch did. You
know, it was weird. I was the only guy
in the office not invited to Brendan's
house to watch football on Sundays. And
I'm like, ah, whatever. You know, I'm
married. I have two kids. I, you know,
I'll watch football with my kids. I
didn't care. Um, but later on,
was it a helenophobic thing?
Sorry, I just wanted to
I think I'm going to go I'm going to go
with that. Yes.
Yeah.
Yes,
you should.
He's prejudiced against Greek people.
There you go. Um,
let me tell you a little story about
John Brennan.
John worked for
John worked for a woman when I first got
hired. Um, he worked for a woman who was
a Syria expert and she wrote this book
called Syria Fragile Mosaic of Power
that we all had to read because it was
like the definitive work on Hafz
al-Assad, Bashar al-Assad's father. M
so John was a GS15 which is the top of
the GS scale um deputy director of of
the analytic group
I'm sorry the general services scale it
starts at one it goes to 15 so he's kind
of a you know senior analyst junior
manager
and um he goes to her one day and she
never really liked him he goes to her
one day and he said listen I've I've
been a 15 for a long time I think I'm
ready to go to the Senior Intelligence
Service, SIS, and that's where you
belong to the whole community. You can
go to the Pentagon, to the White House,
to the State Department, and you're a
big shot.
So, um,
she said, "Not only will you never be a
member of the Senior Intelligence
Service, I don't even want you working
for me anymore. You're fired."
And at the CIA, it's it's unlike any
other agency. At the CIA, if you're
fired, that means you have six weeks to
walk the halls and find another job. And
if you can't find a job in those six
weeks, then they escort you to your car
and take your badge and tell you, "Don't
ever come back again."
Well, it was Christmas
and the normal cycle for jobs is summer.
That's when everybody changes jobs is in
the summertime. Nobody's changing jobs
at Christmas. So he couldn't find a job.
So finally he goes to the PDB staff, the
president's daily brief. Now the
president's daily brief is the most
important document in government. Um,
every morning, six days a week, uh, the
PDB staff briefs the president, the vice
president, the secretaries of state and
defense, the national security um,
advisor,
the CIA director, and all their deputies
on whatever classified events happened
overnight. Okay, it's like 12 pages
long, and the president reads it line by
line while the briefer is sitting there
to answer questions. So he goes to the
PDB staff and he says,"I need a job."
And they said, 'Well, we have one
opening. You're probably not going to
like it. He said, 'I'll take it.
Whatever it is, it was to brief the
lowest ranking person entitled to a PDB
briefing. That was the National Security
Council's director of national uh
director of intelligence programs, okay?
Which just happened to be this guy named
George Tennant.
Well, John and George have identical
personalities. They're mean, loud, ugly,
cigar smoking, wife cheating [__]
both of them.
And they hit it off immediately.
George had just had a heart attack and
he wasn't supposed to smoke. So, he and
John, there used to be a little bodega,
a little stand uh at 17th in
Pennsylvania and the guy sold cigars. So
after the briefing, they would walk out
there and smoke a cigar together every
day. Next thing you know, uh, George
becomes the deputy director of the CIA,
and he promotes John to be the deputy
director of the Office of Neareastern
and South Asian Analysis, that woman's
boss.
So on his first day back in the office,
he called her into his office and he
said, "Now you're fired."
and she retired.
Well, the next thing you know, he's only
in the job for six months. Then he
becomes the station chief in Riad. Uh
he's the direct line between the king
and George Tennant. 9/11 happens. He
comes back and he becomes the executive
director of the CIA, the number three
ranking officer. He's telling everybody
who will listen that he wants to be
Secretary of Defense. And then
he retires
and there was a big wave of retirements
right after 9/11.
He retires and he goes to work for BAE
Systems very briefly and everybody else
ran to the Hillary Clinton campaign.
John was the only one that went to the
Obama campaign.
And he always says that he, you know,
he's not even a registered Democrat. He
voted communist in 1976. He voted for
for Gus Hall. He's always been an
independent, but everybody was going to
either um uh McCain or Clinton. And he
didn't like either McCain or Clinton.
So, he went to Obama and he was the only
one. And then the rest is history.
Okay. So, now you are being interviewed.
Uh, this is a a written interview. This
is uh
No, it was it was taped. Uh Brian Ross
came down to Washington and I met him
over at the ABC studios over on Dale
Street and um you know I decided in the
uh in the days before that interview
that I was going to uh tell the truth no
matter what he asked me because in in
those days before the interview,
President Bush gave a press conference
in which he looked right into the camera
and he said, "We do not torture her. And
I said to my wife, she was also a senior
CIA officer. I said, "He is a bald-faced
liar. He is looking the American people
in the eye, and he's just lying."
And then a couple of days later, he's
walking to the helicopter on the south
lawn of the White House to go to Camp
David for the week, and a reporter
shouts a question about torture. And he
turns and he says, "Well, if there is
torture, it's the result of a rogue CIA
officer."
And I said to my wife, "Brian Ross's
source is at the White House and they're
going to try to pin this on me." I said,
"I'm going to go public. I'm going to
tell the truth."
And so I did. I said three things. I
said that the CIA was torturing its
prisoners. I said that torture was
official US government policy. It was
not the result of a rogue. And I said
that the policy had been personally
approved by the president himself.
The president said the next day he was
asked about my comments and he said, and
I'll never forget the quote. He said, "I
don't know this man. I've never met this
man. I don't know why this man would
throw me under the bus.
It's like, well, that sounds like an
admission that there's a torture
program.
Yes,
you [__]
Yeah, seriously.
Why would he out me like this? This
Why would he Why would he say the
president is responsible for this? What
are you talking about? I'm just the
president,
right? Wow. You know, one of the things,
one of the crazy things that that I
finally saw in the torture report
or in the heavily redacted uh executive
summary of the torture report, we'll
never see the actual torture report. Was
that George Tennant had repeatedly gone
to Dick Cheney to say, "We really,
really need to brief the president on
the torture program."
And Cheney kept saying, "I'll brief the
president on the torture program and
I'll let you know when it's done." So
Cheney finally told
uh B told Tenant that oh I told the
president about the torture program and
the president's signature is on the
authorization,
but Bush still maintains that he didn't
know there was a torture program.
And after all these years, I think I
believe him.
Yeah.
Yeah. So, did Cheney forge it or did or
was he in a drunken stouper and someone
you know?
I I think that
I think that Cheney walked into the Oval
Office with a bunch of papers and said,
"Mr. President, we need your signature
on these. You know, they're not
important. You don't need to read them."
Yeah.
You just sign them and I'll take care of
it. I I I actually think that's what
happened.
Uh this whole thing was Dick Cheny's
idea. All of it.
He's still alive.
Can you imagine? This is a guy that's
had what, like
85 heart attacks
and he had uh heart uh
a pig heart in there or something.
Yeah, he has a pig heart or No, no, it
was the blonde guy from the movie. The
guy fell and hit his head
and he and Dick Cheney got his heart.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's the And then there are people
who are good and die young.
Yeah.
It's uh Yeah,
that's right.
And you got Cheney. Kissinger. Um,
Kissinger is another one. You can't kill
the devil.
I know.
Yeah.
But, uh, okay. So, God. Okay. We're
gonna have to come back for another
interview because this is so good and
there's so many more questions. Leslie,
you you want questions? Then we'll get
to the
Sure thing, Leslie.
Yeah. So, uh, Robbie Martin, who I think
you, uh, know because you gave him a
blurb for his, uh, movie, A Very Heavy
Agenda, wanted me to ask you what you
think, uh, about the anthrax attacks
from, uh, 2000.
Ah, yeah.
It's It's funny, you know, as a country,
we've largely forgotten about those
anthrax attacks.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh so for people who might
not remember about a week after uh 9/11
there was these and anthrax anthrax
attacks uh sent through the mail five
deaths 17 injuries they were sent to the
offices of some Democratic senators Tom
Dashel Patrick Lehey there was someone
accused of it turns out to be false
there's someone who they say they think
did it but he's uh no longer alive and
the case remains unsolved And it was
massive news and was considered and I I
I fair to mention most people assumed it
was part of the September 11th attack
like a ongoing part of the you know the
attack on the Twin Towers at the time
and it's just kind of been forgotten.
Yeah. You know for a long time
many of us just assumed that they were
connected that this was this new world
that we were living in that was full of
terrorism. Um,
and I think it's well documented that
the FBI utterly blew that investigation.
They made accusations against people who
turned out to be innocent. One guy, one
scientist committed suicide. Um, I don't
know the answer to tell you the truth.
Uh,
was it a disgruntled scientist? Was it I
don't think it was a terrorist
terrorist. Um, there's no evidence that
it was a foreign terrorist. Um, I don't
know. I think the conventional wisdom is
is that it was a disgruntled scientist.
And um can you talk about the uh newly
declassified uh FBI report?
Sure.
So this was Yeah, you you can set it up.
This is uh the first of what are
supposed to be or what is supposed to be
a series of reports that are going to be
declassified from the FBI's
investigation post 911. Um, it was it
was released on Saturday evening
ostensibly because it was the 20th
anniversary of the 911 attacks. I think
it was released on Saturday evening
because they thought nobody would pay
attention to it. That's just me. Uh, but
what it what it was was the FBI's
investigation, again, heavily redacted,
but still you can get most of the story
of a couple of Saudis. um one by the
name of uh Fumei who was an official in
the Saudi consulate in Los Angeles and
the other Omar Abayumi who was a Saudi
national living in Los Angeles and their
connections to the 9/11 hijackers or at
least to two of the 9/11 hijackers.
The FBI concluded that Thumedi and
Bayumi were lying to them when they
said, well, in one case, um, Bayumi said
that he had just run into the 9/11
hijackers in a restaurant and he heard
them speaking Arabic and he said, "Hey,
are you Saudi?" "I'm Saudi." "Oh, yeah,
we're Saudi. Nice to meet you." And they
shook hands and they became friends and
he had no idea that they were the 9/11
terrorists. No idea.
Well, there are other FBI sources
documented in this report saying that
that is nonsense that when Bayumi would
go into the Saudi consulate, he was
greeted as somebody who was very
important. People were deferring to him
and he would speak with Thumi that they
were friends. Well, the Saudis forced
Thumi to uh talk to the FBI. uh he had
diplomatic immunity of course
and um the FBI said that one of their
sources who was an employee of the Saudi
consulate in Los Angeles said that
Fumedi
um almost lost his job a number of times
because he kept giving out radical
terrorist fundamentalist pamphlets
inside the the consulate. Now, to make
all of this worse,
the Saudi ambassador to the United
States at the time was Prince Bandar bin
Sultan.
Oh, yeah.
His wife wired $50,000.
He's the guy who called him a simple who
called Osama bin Laden in the simple,
quiet, simple man or something on Larry
King.
That's right.
Not true. Just not true.
Not true.
Yeah.
Not true at all. You know, when I was
when I was stationed in Saudi Arabia, I
knew a lot of Bin Ladens, and 99% of
them are terrific people, right? They're
as western as you and I are. Uh
I won't hold that against them.
They they have houses in Orlando and
Beverly Hills and Manhattan and San
Francisco, and they would rather be here
shopping than, you know, ever step foot
in their own country again. But they've
got this one bad apple and his kids are
bad too, right? His kids are murderers,
too. And so the only flight that was
allowed in the sky in the two weeks
after 9/11 was President Bush ordered
all bin Laden family members out of the
country for their own safety. And so it
took about a week, but every bin Laden
and it was like a hundred of them. They
all finally convened in Orlando. They
got onto a Saudi jet and they got the
hell out.
That was a favor that the Bush family
did to the Bin Laden family for the Bin
Laden family because they had gone back
so many years as business partners and
friends. the the bin Ladens are the
largest
bin Laden the bin Laden group of
companies it's called is the largest um
uh largecale construction firm in the
Middle East right they don't build
buildings they build like airports
or new cities in the desert or the
tallest building in the world that's
going up now in Jedha this is a major
serious uh construction firm and the old
man Abdul Rahman bin Laden
He had 110 sons.
Um, his daughters don't count.
The the Will Chamberlain of uh
Exactly. You know, I asked I asked a
Saudi one time, "Do you have any
children?" And he said, "No,
unfortunately, just five daughters." I
said, "Oh, I'm so sorry."
Anyway,
uh, a Middle East joke, but that was
true. That conversation actually took
place.
So, anyway, um,
the the is in Arabic or in English or
in Arabic. Yeah.
Yeah. And Asfad,
I'm so sorry. You only have five
daughters. So, um,
so Ben, so, uh, Bandar's wife wired
$50,000 to these two clowns that the FBI
believes made its way to the hijackers.
You know, I was I was the notetaker once
in a in a meeting that George Tenned had
with uh with Bandar in the days after
9/11
and um and George blew his stack and he
was screaming at Bandar that we're going
to start killing people and some of
those people may be named Al Saud. You
get it? And he said, "I get it, George.
I get it. I get it." Well, next thing
you know, these Saudi princes who had
been kind of trouble for us or who were
on our list of suspicious people um
began dying.
One of them died in a mysterious onecar
accident on the the Riad de Jetta
highway. One of them went camping and
died of thirst,
which doesn't happen. Um, one of them uh
walked into the desert and disappeared
and was never seen again.
And then the bin Laden family started
coming forward saying, "Listen, we want
to cooperate. We don't want to have
anything to do with him. He's nuts. He's
a murderer."
So, what we said was, "We're going to
kill him one of these days." So, what we
want is DNA. So, if we blow them up and
we have to pick them up in little
two-inch square pieces, we want to be
able to test the DNA. And the Bin Ladens
couldn't get in line fast enough to give
the DNA samples.
So, I don't understand the when uh
Tenant said, "We're going to start
killing
Saudis."
And what what that was a warning.
That was a warning that you're either
with us or you're against us. And if
you're not going to cooperate with 17 of
these guys being Saudi citizens, you're
not going to cooperate. Then we're going
to do it our way.
And so that is what happened to those
three perhaps in those three suspicious
deaths.
That's what we always suspected. The
Saudis just killed him.
Okay, got it. Um, and what does this new
document reveal about the connections?
There's no smoking gun in this document
yet. That was the one thing that was
really disappointing to me. The the FBI
offers up some conjecture, a conjecture.
And
I like that conjecture. That's good.
It's combination of what? Conjecture and
something else.
And Yeah. And context.
Yeah.
I I like that. That's good. and um
and they do clearly come out and say
that they have other sources that one
inside the consulate who are saying that
Thumatti and Bayumi are lying in their
testimony. Um we never knew until this
was released that the FBI believed they
were lying. In fact, we didn't know
until this was released that they were
definitively interviewed.
You know, we always wondered if they
were. We hoped that they were, but we
didn't know.
So, there's nothing really new. There's
no smoking gun, but it does fill in some
of the blanks. And then the White House
said that there are at least four other
documents coming that are uh that are
being redacted now for release.
So maybe by the time that happens, we'll
we'll have something akin to a full
story.
And why do you think Biden's doing this?
Uh oh, actually I realize we don't have
a lot of time. I definitely want your
thoughts on that. I have that question,
but also I don't know how much time you
have left, but some thoughts on
Afghanistan and the pull out there.
Sure. You know, I was always of the of
the opinion that um that the mission was
the mission. We should have stuck with
the mission and the mission was to
destroy al-Qaeda, which we had done by
December of 2001. It wasn't up to us to
rebuild uh Afghanistan. It wasn't up to
us to turn them into uh a western
democracy.
It it wasn't our problem. Uh we we were
there to kill or capture al-Qaeda's
leadership and to uh destroy or disrupt
the rest of the organization, which we
did. I remember being at CIA
headquarters and watching George W. Bush
giving a speech and for the first time
he used the word nation building and
everybody standing around me just
groaned like, "Oh no, we're going to be
there for a decade." Well, we were there
for two decades. I went to Afghanistan
with um with John Kerry in 2011.
And when we first arrived, you know,
they treat you like this VIP and they
take you into the bubble and you're at
the conference table and they're giving
you this classified briefing and the the
briefing is, you know, we have elements
of this unit moving here and this mo
unit's moving there and we killed these
terrorists here and the Hakani network,
we bombed them there and and we're
winning, right? Things are going well.
We're winning. a year from now, we'll be
able to to to take over this whole
swath. So, we get out of there and John
Kerry says to me, "We may actually win
this thing." And I said, "Senator, we're
not going to win this thing." I said,
"This is the same briefing they've been
giving since 2002. They tell everybody
this every single year. One more year,
we're going to win this thing." And he
said, "Really?" I said, "Really? I've
heard this briefing a half a dozen
times."
So, I just never thought we should we
should have been there in the first
place. We had a job to do. We did it by
December of 2001, and we should have
come home.
And what do you think made Biden um I
mean, it seems like releasing this
document wasn't a huge deal necessarily,
but why do you think he responded to the
to pressure to do was throwing some
Yeah. honestly because the
representatives of the 9/11 families
told him that he would not be welcome at
the commemoration unless he released the
documents.
And do you Huh?
That would have been so embarrassing. He
had to release it.
Wow.
Yeah.
And do you think this is also is he
concerned about PR given the response to
his uh I mean I think it's an unfair
attack on him.
I do too.
I do too. or you know,
look, this was Donald Trump's plan and
he implemented Donald Trump's plan. He
actually delayed the implementation of
Donald Trump's plan because Trump wanted
us to be out by May 1st. Um, I think we
we should be out. So, I I don't care
whose plan it was. It makes no
difference to me. It got ugly at the
end, but you know what?
Sometimes things get ugly. It's
And it was ugly during. That's the
thing. And it was ugly during, but no
one talked about it. And what would we
have remained for anyway? You know, the
president of of Afghanistan was really
no more than the mayor of Kabell. The
central government hasn't controlled the
countryside. Well, pretty much ever. Uh
so why why remain? There's no good
reason to remain.
Mhm.
Yeah. Um well, I know you have another
interview, so thank you in 10 minutes
for Yeah. Thank you so much. We want to
give you a
pleasure so much.
Yeah, this is great. Definitely come
back.
Thanks a lot for having me. I appreciate
it and good to see both of you.
Yes. Oh, and anything you want to say
for uh about Assange or
Oh, free Julian Assange. You know,
without Wikileaks, we wouldn't have any
idea what our government was doing. You
know, I think he's a publisher. I think
he's a a journalist. I think he deserves
our thanks. And uh honestly, I don't
believe that the US government has has
any legal cause to hold him.
And shame on the British for caving.
Yeah.
Great. Thank you so much, John.
Thanks. Good to see you.
You, too.
Bye. Bye.
Bye.
That was great, huh?
Yeah. Great. Great interview.
Great interview. Great. I mean, really
good storyteller. Very interesting
person.
Yeah. Very interesting stuff. Very
interesting stuff. Yeah, next time we're
going to have to ask him about the
raids. I'm kind of curious about this
stuff then. Thank you, Frank Havitt.
Katie, this is the best show ever.
Mind-blowing. Wow. That should go might
John should use that on his next book.
Blurb. Yeah.
You know, when they say praise for like
praise for other things, praise for
previous interview.
Yeah.
Outside sounds agrees
for podcast appearances. Yeah.
previously previous reviews of podcast
appearances.
Yeah, that'll get you that'll bump you
on the New York Times uh bestseller list
right there.
But uh yeah, the people have spoken.
That was really interesting. And um it's
so weird how
much the FBI and CIA's pissing contest
[__] everyone.
Not to put too fine a point on it, but
well, you know, I'm a big big true crime
fan, right? This is something this inter
departmental agency scuffles and stuff.
It's like all the way from the bottom to
the top. Like other police departments,
police departments in the same state,
you know, the trooper, the state
troopers in the local PD, none of them
get along. None of them want to talk to
each other. All of them have janky ass
equipment that they bought from their
cousins, uncles, whoevers. Uh that is
not compatible with any of their stuff.
Like they're like it's so wild like how
uncoordinated is. I guess it's you know
it's getting better. I don't but it's
not better. That's just like oh they're
getting better at like tracking people
and stuff like that.
Yeah. Yeah. Really uh
despicable. The torture stuff is
despicable. I I heard him on this other
interview with Robert Shear again like
just describing how they would be sleepd
deprived which your mind like you start
losing your mind after a certain number
of days
and then your organs also start to to
fail after a certain number of days. I
think it was like 12 days or something
and the CIA was allowed to do it for 14
or something totally obscene. I mean,
this is all obscene obviously anyway,
but obscene within even pretending to
care about any medical rules.
Yeah, it's completely obscene. It was
just straight up a torture pro program.
And the thing about it, like it just
didn't work. And they lied about any
information they got from it was a lie.
They got all the information from like,
you know, the regular interrogation
techniques where you like buy them a cup
of coffee and
Yeah. I've seen I've seen those shows.
Yeah. Well, even like I mean obviously
cops don't use those techniques in real
life. They like our cops like using
torture too for some reason. It's almost
like the point is not it's almost like
the point isn't to stop crime or
anything. It's probably maybe it's just
a bunch of sadist. That's what's scary
is that you get statist, but then you
also get people and I don't, you know,
the show is not a source of propaganda,
but you get people who I think they
sometimes actually think that they're
going after the right person even though
it's the wrong person. But I guess it's
one of those things. It's like, are they
lying? Are they stupid? or they're paid
lot paid not to know, you know, like
when they bend the rules, do they
actually sometimes think mistakenly that
that the bag that the innocent guy is
guilty?
I mean, let's let's I can break it down
because I'm listening to this really
great uh true crime book. Let me pull up
the name of it. uh if people are
interested in I know there's lots of
true crime heads out there and this
one's really good because it's a really
it's a really academic one. So it's
called American Serial Killers the
Epidemic Years. It's a brand new book
and it comes at it from a very academic
perspective about like serial killing
and like what are the sociological
factors that create people who become
serial killers. But it goes through like
all these stories about like
It's appropriate for a CIA show. Yeah.
Yeah. But all these cops and stuff and
how they react to these crimes and then
they open the story with like the
Jeffrey Dmer case. And I don't know if
people know this, but the cops actually
walked back one of Jeffrey Dmer's
victims to him, a child who had
who was like bleeding and had been
tortured. and they walked it back
because they assumed that oh it was just
some gay thing.
Yes.
So it's like
that was so disgusting. I heard about
that from someone and I like wanted to
throw up.
And did you know that it almost happened
twice?
No. when the people who the cops who
actually arrested Jeffrey Dawnmer very
similar situation a guy escaped and he
was handcuffed and the cops were you
know trying to like brush past it even
after walking into the apartment
spelling the dead bodies they and the
guy was telling this guy is trying to
kill me he told me he was going to eat
my heart the cops were still like oh
this is just some gay thing now they
kept looking they it until they actually
saw the pictures of like dead bodies and
actual people.
They were still of the mind of kind of
like this is just some kind of gated
some caught at this point. They didn't
like this kid back in the clutches of
Don.
No, but they were about to until they
actually saw corpses.
Even the smell didn't stop him. It was
it was the pictures of the actual
corpses and when they actually
discovered the corpses there up until
that point they they smelled the
corpses. The guy was saying, "This guy's
trying to kill me." But they were still
like, "Oh, this is just some thing.
Let's we don't want to fill out the
paperwork."
Oh my god. That is honestly it's it's
like one of the worst stories I've ever
heard about walking them. I I can't even
I knew that. I didn't twice. It
happened.
I mean, the second
and so this idea that we always have
that the that the cops are the vanguard
against all this like No.
No, I never thought. Yeah, I never
thought that. But even in those cases,
that's disturbing because they actually
think and it's like for [__] up
reasons, right? Cuz they're like they
like pathize
gay behavior.
Yeah.
But that's even it's like scary that
they actually I mean I guess that's the
bias, you know.
Yeah. And this wasn't a 100 years ago.
This was like the 19 you know this is
pretty you know. So this Yeah. the
dimmable line is not something that you
know protects us even like even and so
that's the real problem with propaganda
like even though you know everybody who
watches all those cop shows knows that
they're fake and not real you assume
that some it's like 10% of the cops
might might like that when it's more
like you know it's a whole system and
nobody acts like this like yeah
the the cops aren't aren't this line of
defense that are helping us and
protecting us from the they're the
accessories a lot of the times, you
know.
You know.
Yeah. Well, uh I wanted to It's so It's
so disturbing. I wanted to uh because
we're talking about 9/11, I thought it
would be a good idea to um look at a
a video that Meet the Press put
together.
Hold on one second.
Well, there are two videos I wanted us
to look at. Um,
one is an interesting CBS uh uh piece
and then one is on Face the Nation.
Let's look at this. Let's look at this
one first.
The FBI has released a
No, not that one. Sorry. I was going to
just play I'm sorry I didn't but hold
on. Hi. Hi, Nick. Everyone say hi to
Nick.
One second, please. Um,
okay. This is a good one.
Welcome back to Face the Nation. Late
last night, the FBI released a newly
declassified document related to the
investigation of the 9/11 terror
attacks.
No, not this one.
Contact hijackers had with Saudi
associates here in the US. It did not
include any evidence that the Saudi
government was complicit. Holly Williams
is in Riad with a look at how that
It's not moving for me. I just
Oh, yeah. It's not moving for me either.
Alrison, Saudi Arabia.
Hold on. What's happening here, guys?
Uh, it's not working.
Let's try that again.
Uh, also where is my
Hold on.
Okay.
Um, I'll just Should I play it?
Okay, I'll play it.
Hold on.
Tell me if this works.
Can you guys see this and hear this?
Yes.
Welcome back to Face the Nation. Late
last night, the FBI released a newly
declassified document related to the
investigation of the 911 terror attacks
outlining contact
with Saudi associates here in the US. It
did not include any evidence that the
echoit
is in Riad with a look at how that
country is fighting.
Maybe just mute your mic while it's
playing.
I don't Will you be able to here? Let me
try this. What about this
against extremist
now? Can you hear it?
Yeah.
Okay. Here.
At Alrison, Saudi Arabia claims it's
reforming convicted terrorists with
music
sports. This is your coffee shop.
Yep. Exactly.
And even a coffee shop the prisoners run
themselves. Our guide was an inmate,
Yasa Isam Hamdi, born a US citizen to
Saudi parents in Baton Rouge, Louisiana.
I was there for five.
Oh, my hometown.
Very nice. It was a very nice
experience.
Bizarrely, many inmates wore business
suits during our visit and others filmed
it.
Now, just this is not like from the uh
tourism uh chamber of commerce or
something from Saudi Arabia. This is for
Face the Nation on CBS
said for the prison's TV station. Saudi
officials accompanied us at all times
and denied allegations of torture at the
facility. After growing up mainly in
Saudi Arabia, Hamdi told us he traveled
to Afghanistan to train with the Taliban
just before the 9/11 attacks.
I watch action movies a lot and I wanted
like to have uh I want to try I want to
try doing stuff like that. He was
captured, held in Guantanamo Bay and
then US military prisons before agreeing
to give up his American citizenship and
returning to Saudi Arabia a free man. He
was later arrested by Saudi authorities
though he was vague about why.
I don't want to speak about it a lot.
Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Uh but uh talking and stuff like
that and because of that I came back to
prison. But Hamdi and several other
prisoners were happy to describe their
upbringing in an ultra-conservative
closed off kingdom exposed to religious
fundamentalism if you weren't looking
for extremism. Yeah,
if you weren't looking for
fundamentalism.
Exactly. You can find them. You can find
them. You can learn from them and they
will misguide you.
The same factors helped radicalize the
15 September 11th hijackers who were
Saudi citizens according to some. And
Saudi Arabia has been criticized for
being slow to fix the problem. Now Saudi
Arabia says it's reforming. Extremist
preaching been banned. Women have
greater freedom than ever before.
By the way, I can't help notice this
like this weird sword shot
has been criticized for being slow to
fix the problem. Now Saudi Arabia says
it's reforming. Right after talking
about reforming
banned women have greater freedom than
ever before including finally the right
to know I kind of wish
justified violence against non-Muslims
have been
he's not wearing his mask right
tries to rehabilitate its image and
stamped out extremism
Hamdi told us he's also been
successfully reformed
all people do mistakes I did the mistake
I was an extremist extremist once, but
now I am not.
I like the fade.
The Saudi government has always denied
any 911 attacks. Country has people make
mistakes to combat terrorists, but is
still widely criticized over.
Why are they doing this now? It seems
like such a a hand job.
I guess that's what they're there for. I
guess they asked. I guess they put the
call like all right kind of
it it just seemed like what the problem
was for me was that didn't seem to have
a lot to offer to the American viewers
like it wasn't like a big touristy pitch
like has been going on right no more
reform reform is here
it's weird it's like something you would
see like in like a country we had bombed
a few years ago like that would be the
followup like oh this is Libya now like
this is the like when but the this, you
know, KSA press tour started off with
like, oh, we have WWE shows, right?
Like, oh, I uh KSM well I hang out with
uh The Rock and [__] Like they were
hanging out with like Hollywood stars.
It was a big like media push, media
blitz originally and then the, you know,
dismemberment happened and now they're
coming to us with the like, for lack of
a better term, like the third world
nation is doing good type puff piece
when before it was like, "Oh, we're
here. We got all this money. We're just
like we're like, you know, China has all
this money now. Hey, we do too now and
like look at us. Come visit us."
Yeah. Yeah. It's very It's weird. It's
uh it's it's very
it's it's like a little bit too over the
top for for I just think it's bad PR, I
guess.
Yeah. It's not the good PR, especially
when propaganda when you were so
bombastic when it was so bombastic
before when it was really about the
glitz and the glamour, you know? So like
like all these lane these humble people
are, you know, just learning to, you
know, enter the modern world now
finally.
Yeah.
Um, and then I thought there was another
video we could react to that's uh has
this was from uh Meet the Press this
weekend.
Oh yeah. Oh, and people are asking about
Nicki Minaj. We could give our
Oh, we got to do that. Okay. Well, let's
should we watch Should we do that? I
think we have time for both. Can we do a
quick uh face and nation?
Sure.
And then we'll do then we'll end on
Nikki.
Sorry, not face. Uh yeah, hold on.
Um, when the towers began
Okay, let me unmute this. Tuck tad.
This is uh meet the press. Okay,
it's been a weekend of remembrance
recalling that day 20 years ago on
September 11th when our world suddenly
changed. We asked 10 people, some of
whom were in government, others who
helped us through that terrible time, to
tell us of their experience that day and
their reflections on the two decades
that followed.
That day was a day where we thought it
was going to be an easy day.
I was actually in a meeting caddy corner
from the White House.
My daughter called me and told me to
turn on the TV.
What's most vivid to me on that day is
hearing the the first report and
thinking it was an accident. I actually
saw with my own eyes the second plane at
I heard the capital police
evacuate. Get out of here right away.
I just told him a second plane hit the
second tower. America was under attack.
When the towers began to collapse, the
entire country shuddered. And I said on
the air at that point,
wow,
this changes. It was a a a shock to
really the the presumption amongst the
American people that we were somehow
immune from attack.
We came together
in a way that I've never seen in my
lifetime. And what was really powerful,
okay, Joe Tory,
was they were bringing pictures
of their lost relatives and friends with
Yankee caps or Yankee jerseys, uh,
jackets, and saying what big fans they
were. I I realized that baseball was
necessary for, I guess, to start the
healing. in the first day
he just did to baseball what he went CBS
did to uh Saudi Arabia the Muslim faith
is not a faith of of terror it's a faith
of love a lot of people's commitment to
our country was brought into question um
overlooking the fact that there are
scores of Muslims who serve in our law
enforcement communities I was one of
them
one of the greatest spontaneous
series of remarks by any president in
history were the remarks that the
president gave at ground zero.
I can hear you. The rest of the world
hears you. And the people
and the people who knocked these
buildings down will hear all of us soon.
The authorization to use military force
was passed on 914, three days by three
days after this horrific uh terrible
attack. That was the wrong time to pass
such an overly broad uh authorization.
We underestimated the uh complexity of
the war that we were about to get into.
And I think a lot of people thought we
could just walk in and clean it up.
We got into some
I wonder why they thought that
we had to quote because you told them to
that that was going to happen.
In many ways an endless war probably the
right
uh narrative the right I mean we send
people to their death in Korea. I think
that would have been the right way. My
friend,
we cannot remake.
Yeah. So this guy, it says homeland
security. They leave out that he's at
Rathon on the border of Rathon. Can you
imagine?
I say it's really offensive. We need to
think about Afghanistan.
A sad mistake that we went into that
started to end that sense of unity.
Look at that hair color. Oh god. Torture
analogy would have been Korea.
Walk in and clean it up. we got into
some sense that we had to quote end the
war and it is in many ways an endless
war. Probably the right
uh narrative the right uh analogy would
have been Korea. I think that would have
been the right way to think about
Afghanistan.
Why what so can you expand on your
objections?
Well, first of all, that's that's an
insane thing to say. Korea and Korea is
like actually a country of like a people
that was split in half by us, not
Afghanistan. Like that's a complete
those countries are not nowhere near
comparable. The re like I don't even
that's just a bizarre thing. Like that's
just a bizarre comparison to make. Like
we still occupy Korea like like we're
still occupying
uh doing it. Maybe that's why she's
comparing them. That's not like a good
thing and that's not like that's not
good for Koreans who are cut off from
you know people who they knew their
families the other half of Korea like
that and I hate Condi so much because
she I mean all the Bush admit admin
officials got away with it but people
like praised her just because she was a
black woman like and straight up like
she was the first black woman who was
such and such such and such but she was
like evil and she's just treated like
with respect. They allowed her to get
into the NFL cuz she loves football.
Like she has never faced any sort of
like even like negativity really for and
like she's personally like close to
George W. Bush. Not just like she didn't
just work for him. They are personally
close to one another.
So like she is absolutely complicit in
anything that that administration does.
But nobody has a problem with her.
Yeah. Yeah,
that's true. Hey, and Jed Johnson is the
guy who who they don't announce is um is
that Rathon. It may be the other
company. What's the other big one?
Rathon and um
oh
what's the other one?
Lucky Martin.
Yeah, it's one of those two. Forgive me
if I'm wrong about which one. Um
okay. not remake a whole country and
prop up another country's government in
a distant land.
Bad mistake that we went into Iraq that
started to end that sense of unity.
Our response over time particularly when
we got distracted or you know refocused
on the Iraq war
again the narrative that the Afghanistan
war was a good one
became very militarized. I worry.
Wait, did she say we became very
militarized?
Hold on.
Our government would be too polarized to
our response over time, particularly
when we got distracted or, you know,
refocused on the Iraq war became very
militarized.
I worry.
So, we became f militarized in our focus
that if there were another 911 today,
oh, this is good. our government would
be too polarized to summon a national
response.
So we couldn't even do nation building
and uh invade another country. That's
how you know in today's political
climate
just too polarized to
thank God we're it wasn't like that back
then. We could get two wars under our
belts. Um I mean addition to all the all
the other ones
to that event. I worry that if we don't
deal with our internal divisions,
we'll never be able to do another war.
We'll be vulnerable to another kind of
degradation of uh America's security,
America's values, and America's future.
We've got to come back.
You're the one who degraded.
I know the torture attacks happened
under your I mean, but to be fair, why
would she know? It only she only got a a
daily presidential briefing that said n
uh Osama bin Laden to attack
inside the United States.
Yeah. Weird.
Jesus Christ.
Enough with Okay. Um enough with 911. It
seems the epitome of neoliberal
hypocrisy to mourn that event 20 years
later when this event killed millions of
people. No one outside the US can even
bear to read this. I mean, I don't think
we do a bad job on this show of uh
ignoring the uh
the fallout in other countries of 911.
Um know your audience writing the
writing a message. Thank you for the
$10. Who are you talking to though? Like
I think
you're talking to us. I think maybe
maybe they were talking to the people on
MSNBC.
Yes. Who was doing? Yes. Okay. Yes. So,
thank you for knowing your audience.
Yes.
Um, so but moving to on to more
important stories uh and more important
wars and beefs. Leslie, you want to tell
us something about uh
Nicki Minaj? So Nicki Minaj finally
finally finally is canled. Finally.
Thank God. I I feel such a relief. I've
never been a Nicki Minaj fan. And
finally, the Barbs have been defeated
online because Nicki
and Barbs are um Nicki fans, right?
Nikki's fans, right? And so for some
bizarre reason Nicki Minaj, who I think
has never been an intelligent person,
right? Has nothing of value to say as
far as I know. For some reason, she was
propped up as like some sort of feminist
icon around like 2015, but I think it
was just like a like white writers at
like Jezebel and [__] who were like
trying to vampirically like suck the
cool the black coolness from her, but uh
I never knew why they propped her up.
Cardi B is actually cool, but Nicki
Minaj I never thought was actually like
cool or had anything really going on
besides her music. And I mean, we I
don't even want to get into the dark
[__] with her husband being like a
[__] rapist or whatever. I don't
know. We don't even have to get into
that. But uh she decided to take to
social media to complain
to warn people about the fact that she
heard from her cous.
Yeah.
Yeah. She heard from her cousin that he
got vaccinated and his ball his paws
went that big or stretched out
something. I I actually forgot because I
have in my head um this Trinidadian uh
newscaster who gave this commentary on
it's very funny and he said you go
around telling people your cousin got a
flat tire.
Do we have that? Can we watch that?
Oh yeah. Let me pull that up. Let's pull
that. Actually that's the that's the
best thing actually. Yeah, we got the
clip from Joy. So, you saw and this
turned into a big thing because Joanne
Reed responded to it.
Joanne Reed responded to it because and
just with the typical like how dare you
say this about you know the vaccine they
did the liberal you know thing which I'm
not complaining about especially in this
instance but you do see like you know
it's it's a pattern at this point. some
[__] celebrity says something about
COVID that's not real and then we make a
big show of like how stupid they are and
how stupid you
but it doesn't really seem to like
change like anything
as far as like or like get through to
any other side. Uh but this one was
actually like at least it was funny. At
least it was funny with with the news.
But let me
Okay, I can in the meantime I can also
um I can
I It's so funny. Every time you like
that video was all over the internet all
day. The second you want to find it,
it's like
it's always like that.
Well, here's here's here's the Okay. Um
so she's she said this came this this
was because she wouldn't get vaccinated
for the um Met Gala. Here it is. Can you
guys see?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. They want you to get
vaccinated for the Met. If I get
vaccinated, it won't be for the Met.
It'll be once I feel I've done enough
research. I'm working on that now. In
the meantime, my loves, be safe. Wear
the mask with two strings that grip your
head and face, not the loose one. And
then um
uh in response to a fan uh who said that
blogs may drag the story, Nikki shared
that she's not worried. Who cares what
blogs going to do? Y'all always worried
about blogs. This is my real f, you
know, FKN life. they can choke. And here
was where she like started making a
public health announcement. Um, my
cousin in Trinidad won't get the vaccine
uh cuz his friend
got it and became impotent. His
testicles became swollen. His friend was
weeks away from getting married. Now the
girl called off to the wedding. So just
pray on it and make sure you're
comfortable with your decision, not
bullied.
Yeah, I'm sure that happened, Nikki. I'm
sure that 100% happened.
Yeah. So, uh, someone wrote, uh, some
random guy in Trinidad blamed CO for
catching an FBI while cheating, and now
look what he caused.
Yes. Everybody was saw immediately that
that was totally a [__] madeup story.
Um, I just sent you the video of the
response. Oh. Oh, you can play. Yeah,
play Joy.
Should we play this one first? Okay.
Yeah, I haven't seen Joy.
Oh, I'm sure this one is probably going
to be annoying.
She does seem broken up.
Nikki always sucked. Like I don't know
what the what's new. Nikki always sucks.
She never had any. I'm sorry. I never
liked her.
Well, did you see her response though?
Oh,
this is what happens when you're so
thirsty to down another black woman by
the request of the white man that you
didn't bother to read all my tweets. My
god, sister do better. Imagine getting
your dumb ass on TV a minute after tweet
to spread a false narrative about a
black woman.
I mean, I don't see how it's false.
Nikki, I'm sorry. I don't I Joanne was
right. I don't know what you're
I know it's weird to say that, right?
Isn't it a weird feeling?
Tomiana purpos and then she calls her
Tomiana. Um Uncle Tomiana, she called
her another tweet purposely chose to
ignore these tweets and others. I wonder
why. Uh and then uh Uncle Tomiana asked
why on who on earth would trust us, the
FDA guys? Uh
it is very funny. And Nicki Maj is
getting in a fight with Joanne Reed on
Asan got into it. uh to um Hassan [__]
Hassan Per not not not Hassan. Yeah,
Hassan [__] got it into it and Nicki
Minaj quote tweeted him. It wasn't
anything testy, but it was there when
she revealed that the you that the
president reached out to Nicki to talk
about her uh like to talk to her about
this. Did you know that this part that
no
the president is
Biden our president or
Yes. Yes. our our president has uh
reached out to my president. Uh
yeah, I did not know that. Yeah, I sent
it's the second link I sent you.
Okay, hold on. One thing she did say is
that um that uh Minaj said she called
Joyce a lying homophobic coun.
I can say it.
Okay, you want to say it? So say the
three words together. She Yeah, she
called Reed a lying homophobic [__]
which shows that Nikki She looks up her
Ah, sorry. Oh my god, that was the worst
moment. I meant to to Sorry, say that
again. She looks up I I closed on you
instead of the instead of the screen.
Yeah, she looks on her up her opponent
so she knew to look up Joanne Reed stuff
and wasn't just like right
uh out she wasn't just popping off.
Yeah. And she I mean, look, again, I'm
I'm It's very weird. I agree with I
don't agree with Minaj, I'll say, on
this, but she is right about the lying
homophobic part.
Yeah, she is.
I mean, that is true. So, she, as you
said, she did her research. Okay. So, uh
Nick, can we play the the video that's
in the that Leslie sent?
I sent this. There's two link. I sent
three links. This we can look at the
second one, which is the um Jen Saki.
Okay, one second.
Oh my gosh, this is going to be good.
Calls to be a difference of opinion
between Nicki Minaj and the White House
about
there's a difference between Nicki Minaj
and the White House.
An invitation to Nicki Minaj to come
here.
We offered a call uh with Nicki Minaj uh
and one of our doctors to answer
questions she had about the safety and
effectiveness of the vaccine. Uh this is
pretty standard and something we do all
the time. It was a very early stage call
at a staff level, staff to staff. Um and
we weren't even at the point of
discussing or we're not even at the
point of discussing I should say at this
point um the mechanisms or the format or
anything along those lines. It was
simply an offer to have a conversation
and uh an early stage call.
You think that's going to happen?
We'll see. I don't have anything to
predict for you. making the not just 22
million Twitter followers. Why not
invite her to the White House? Have a
conversation and make it a big public.
Is this a Barb and Undercover Barb
recommendations on our communications
advice? Karen, you are quite
experienced. Um, look, I will say um
you may note to call her and we've a
bunch before that we are not always the
right um platform or the right voice,
right? Sometimes that's because people
may not like the president. Um
Whoa. Humble, Jen. Okay. Yeah. And then
we can watch the other one which is a
really great summary of it.
Is that the first or the third?
Third one.
This one dropped yesterday morning and
as the story dropped it was excitement.
Now Nicki Minaj
no stranger to controversy. Um I mean
she was here for carnival in 2020 and
that was a bakanal which
well her husband now husband an Iowa um
she would have made some outlandish
statements over the years but this one
takes the cake. This is almost like what
you would hear by a parlor where
somebody will tell you well your cousin
friend
neighbor say xyz. I mean come on Nikki
you have 180 million followers. People
listen to you, people follow your
particular lead. You going on the social
media space and talking about your
cousin friend, take the vaccine and get
impotent
and all of a sudden, you know, marriage
call off and some kind of bakanal story.
I mean it's irresponsible on all
fronts irresponsible based on the
misinformation that is going out there
regarding this vaccine. Um you know
there was no verification of the story
and furthermore even on a personal note
even if this is the case to expose your
cousin friend's flat tire in the public
domain like that. If the man have a flat
tire, okay, he will work on that. You
know, the just herbs and and and and
punch and the man could eat and bring
back our vibes. But don't come now and
talk that kind of talk. The thing get so
hot.
Jake Tapper on CNN yesterday at 4:00
talk about this with Dr. Fouchy. Dr.
voucher is of course the US uh that's
their their lead leading mine and and
and specialists with this whole co 19 uh
push back and the fight against the 19
I love the light
you know like the man was blindsided
answer
I mean I don't think we should per se
but but Nikki
better than that I I honestly expected
better and besides um obviously that
outlandish statement and she always
talks about Trinidad and she's from
Trinidad. She's yet to collaborate with
somebody from here.
What?
That's a talk for another program on
another day.
Whoa. Can we get this guy on the show?
We very very good.
That was great. Wow. Flat tire.
Flat tire.
It happens. He makes it sound like he
knows that condition. Is that a thing?
I mean, he Well, I think he just means
like is impotent. Impotent.
Oh, that's what it is. I thought it was
I thought he was saying Oh, okay. I just
want to drop.
Oh, I thought it was by the balls. I
Okay, that's why I was like flat tire. I
thought
in the public domain like that.
Got it.
Okay.
Okay. Okay. Please playing there. Every
man has a flat tire.
In the public domain like that. Every
man have a flat tire. Okay. He will work
on that. You know, there just herbs and
and and and punch and certain things man
could eat and bring back our vibes.
Yeah. bring back.
I see. Okay, got it.
So, he's saying that you can find
medical cures for uh imp his cousin in
the streets.
Yeah. Seriously.
Um flat tire. I see. Yeah. I Okay.
I like that though. Punch. I like a
punch. Is there a punch?
That's That sounds
There's a punch.
Yeah.
Anyway, well, this was a great show. Uh,
do let me see any Patreons that we got.
I mean, we got a lot of generous uh
donations.
Oh, come on. We got to get one Patreon,
guys.
No, if you like this show, guys, did you
like the show? I know a lot of you did
because a lot of you guys said how great
the show was. So, you know what to do.
You just go to patreon.com/thekatyhelper
show. Again, that's patreon.com. I can't
do it. patreon.comthecatyhelper
show. I always when I try to do a
Caribbean, it like turns into Scottish.
I don't know why. Um, and
just drop some some Patreon love.
patreon.com/thekatyhalper
show. Let's see.
How do I do this? It's so demoralizing.
Leslie, what do you do? You just ask.
You just say how great it is to join and
then people do it.
Yeah. Yeah. You just And just talk about
the recent episodes. That's it.
Oh, recent episodes. You know what
you'll get on Patreon? Oh, really great
stuff, actually. You'll get me
unfiltered
on
uh Well, let's see. Let me think of a
good Patreon. Oh, well, we're coming
soon is a really great Patreon on uh the
Texas
uh Texas
abortion ban. This is an audio Patreon.
Let me think of what's video Patreon.
Um,
oh, you know what you're going to get
soon? A little Rose McGawan. I could
actually tease some of that without you
because I know you have to go. But yeah,
you guys want to hear from Rose McGawan.
Rose McGawan, guys, become Patreon
supporters. Unreleased. And here's what
you're going to get if you're a Patreon.
First of all, you should be like, "Oh my
god, this show was so good tonight that
I should become a Patreon right away."
But then you know what else you can come
for?
Come to the Patreon for forthcoming
interviews with
never before release interviews with
Rose McGawan
and
Gabbor Mate.
Rose McGawan. Gabbor Mate.
Uh we'll be doing more self-care stuff
also. Um you know I don't agree. I said
this before about the Rose McGowan
thing. I don't like Larry Elder and I
wouldn't endorse him even though I also
have disdain for Gavin Newsome, but I'm
not going to judge someone who had
personal experience with Gavin Newsome's
wife. It reminds me of the Wanita Brick
thing. I get this uh this a lot when I
mention her, but I don't know like if
you had something happen to you, I
understand why you're going to support
that person's opponent.
And so Rose McGowan says that uh Gavin
Newsome's wife tried to uh like
discredit her and smear her.
And uh
I think that that makes it
understandable
just like I think it's understandable
that Wanita Brick who says Bill Clinton
raped her uh endorsed Donald Trump even
though I don't like Donald Trump. But we
can't keep expecting people to to not
live by their
through their own experiences.
So, you don't have to like Larry Elder,
but
I don't know. So, anyway, but I have
this really amazing interview with her
where she goes through why uh
why she
does not consider herself a Democrat and
she talks about the Clintons and she
talks about uh Kla Harris and it all
starts with how upset she was over Kla
Harris speaking with Bill Clinton at an
event on
empowering women and girls.
Yeah. Anyway, what else? Anything else,
Leslie?
Oh, no. Um, by everyone, make sure to
check us out. Um, uh, check out Struggle
Session. Uh, if you enjoy the show at
patreon.com/struggression.
We, uh, going to have a upcoming episode
on Candyman, the old and the new
version. I think I talked a little bit
on the show about how great the old
version uh, was and how it's about like
gentrification and all this stuff. very
very uh good movie. We uh have an
upcoming episode on some pro wrestling.
And in fact, if anybody's, you know, if
you're staying up tonight, head over to
twitch.tv/
uh struggle session tonight because I
will be doing a wrestling show. It won't
not on my channel. It's just that if I
tell this guy's name, nobody's going to
remember it. But at least if you go to
struggle session, you'll find where
we're hosting because we're doing a
little pro wrestling show after the
fact. His name is Nude Tane Salary Mane,
but you you might not find on Twitch,
but just follow me on Twitter.
Twitter.com Leslie Lee. I'll tweet out
in a second if you want to watch some
wrestling in about an hour.
Yeah. Um, all right. I'm going to stay
on for five more minutes, but have a you
you get ready for your show, Les.
All right. Thank you so much. Have a
good night, everyone.
Thanks. You, too. Bye.
Just want to make sure that people
understand. Uh my point is not that
Larry Elder is the same as Gavin
Newsome. My point is that if you have
something happen in your personal life
with someone that may determine your
politics and I can't judge people who do
that. You know what I'm saying? Does
that make any sense? I don't know why I
respond to one person in the chat who
seems to think that I'm equating Elder
and Newsome. I mean, Newsome is a [__]
li and a disappointment and he has blood
on his hands, but uh, you know, Elder is
worse. That's what I say. But I also get
what she's doing. If I had an
interaction with uh Newsome's wife, I'd
probably be trying to get my story out
there. And sometimes the media doesn't
pay attention to your story unless you
do something like that.
So the point is you become Patreon
supporters, you'll get access to that
interview and it's and it's uh a longer
interview. Other people are going to get
uh very small little little gems. Uh all
right, I will uh see you guys all soon.
Thank you so much for coming to the
Katie Haler Show. This was a great
interview. I'm going to do another one
with uh John, which will be Patreon only
as well. and I will see you either next
week uh maybe Sunday. Not sure if I'm
going to be doing a show then, but uh
make sure you subscribe because I do
some kind sometimes I just do these um
you know shooting from the hip uh not
planned just reacting to the news shows.
Also, please put in this comment in
under this video, put in the chat uh
some shows or movies on Amazon that you
would want me and Leslie or me and other
guests to basically do a um mystery
science theater with, you know what I
mean? And then we'll donate some of the
the the the'll
have to be on Twitch and we'll donate
that'll be a Patreon only thing but
we'll donate some money to uh you anti-
Amazon organizing because that you have
to do through Amazon unfortunately.
Okay. So any Amazon Prime shows let me
type this up actually.
Please
suggest
series or movies on Amazon Prime. My
thing has to be you want
us to
uh
have
parties.
Mr. Science Theater.
All right. See you guys soon. Bye
everyone. Thanks, Nick. Thanks, Brad.
Thanks, Rushka. Thanks, Tyler.